Guide to the New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites MSS.496
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Hoffman, Elizabeth, November 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of https://wp.nyu.edu/elizabeth_hoffman/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a calendar of her events, reviews and articles about Hoffman and her works, information about her published music, and images of her. The compositions featured on the site are electroacoustic, making use of computers and traditional instruments, and avant-garde. Hoffman's pieces are composed for opera, orchestral, solo, and ensemble performance. Site capture began in November 2017. This description is based on the November 2017 capture of the site.
- Holcomb, Robin, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5929; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.robinholcomb.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, news related to her music, audio files, photo gallery, a list of upcoming events, and contact information. Holcomb is a pianist, composer, librettist, singer, and songwriter. Capture of the site began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Holzborn, Damon, April 2014- ongoing; 15 websites in 15 archived websites.
  New site crawls are accrued semiannually. Art projects were captured as a one-time as a sample.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://damonholzborn.com/ and rustle.works in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a discography of his works, examples of his compositions in the form of embedded audio files, information about his projects in the realm of art, and two pieces of music writing and manipulating code that Holzborn has written. The pieces featured on the site are primarily computer music, featuring electronic instruments and improvisation. Capture of the site began in May 2014. The crawls related to Holzborn also include Rustle Works, a software studio formed as a partnership between musician/developer Holzborn and writer/filmmaker Betsy Nagler. The studio combines technology, music, and storytelling to create tools, games, and art projects. The website contains information and links to their projects. Project include twitter bots and art projects Tap Hear, Disting mk4 Quick Guide, and with w/. With George Lewis, also created Personal Bayou and Personal Shout, two digital art installations. It also includes the Exquisite Coasts, Quaxtrip, and Coast Express, which were projects created by Holzborn for musicians to play together remotely in response to the COVID-19 pandemic.
- Honstein, Robert, February 2014- ongoing; cuid5891; 9 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://roberthonstein.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains news regarding his work, a biography of the artist, calendar of upcoming events, and a long list of his compositions. Honstein is a composer of orchestral, chamber, and vocal music. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Horvitz, Wayne, July 2017- ongoing; cuid5913; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.waynehorvitz.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of his works, discography, writings and scores, information on his teachings, an online store, contact information, and a calendar of his events. Horvitz is a composer, pianist, and electronic musician who has performed around the world. Capture of the site began in July 2017. This description is based on the July 2017 capture of the site.
- Hough, Matthew, February 2014-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of matthewhough.com and houghhousemusic.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Crawls were also rescoped to include Youtube and Soundcloud embedded materials.
  This is the professional website of Matthew Hough, a composer and guitarist based in the San Francisco Bay area. Hough composes music for chamber ensemble, vocal ensemble, and solo instrumentalists, as well as ensembles with variable instrumentation, and rearranges others' compositions for guitar. This site features a biography of the artist, news about upcoming releases and performances, a selection of the artist's work available for streaming with score, a full discography and catalogue of compositions, and links to some of Hough's writings on music. This site was first captured in February of 2014. This description is based on the November 2019 crawl of the site. The site has not changed significantly except to reflect performances, compositions, and recordings of Hough's since 2014. Also includes the website for composer and guitarist Matthew Hough's music publishing company, Hough House, through which he publishes and sells the scores for his compositions. The site features audio and video recordings of performances of the pieces, as well as links to the composer's professional site, which features the artist's biography, news and upcoming performances, a discography with streaming links, links to press coverage of Hough's works, and links to the composer's prose writings.
- Hron, Terri, November 2017- ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.birdonawire.ca/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded Soundcloud audio and Vimeo video files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  Terri Hron is a musician, a performer and a multimedia artist. Her work explores historical instrumental performance practice and repertoire, field recording, ceramics, movement and video. The website contains a biography of the artist, information about her works and projects, a discography of her published albums, and information about taking lessons with her. The compositions featured on the site make use of the recorder as well as electronic instruments. Site capture began in November 2017. This description is based on the November 2017 capture of the site.
- Hunt, Jerry, July 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.jerryhunt.org/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a discography and videography, as well as descriptions of, his works, prose writings by and about Hunt, and a description of the method by which Hunt committed suicide. Hunt's music made use of computers and electronic instruments as well as video. Capture of the site began in July 2017. This description is based on the July 2017 capture of the site.
- Ibarra, Susie, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.susieibarra.com/susieibarra/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Iconis, Joe, February 2014- ongoing; cuid5878; 4 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://MrJoeIconis.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, list of theater productions, a poster gallery, list of songs from the television show "Smash," calendar of his events, concert reviews, online store, and contact information. Iconis is a pianist, composer, lyricist, bookwriter, and has authored many musicals. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Jacobsen, Colin, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://colinjacobsen.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded image files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains a biography of composer and violinist Colin Jacobsen, a calendar of his events, examples of his compositions in the form of embedded audio files, information about his works arranged by genre, and links to reviews and articles written about Jacobsen and his music. The compositions featured on the site are classically-influenced instrumental pieces for chamber, orchestral, and choral ensembles. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the October 2017 capture of the site.
- Jeziorski, Milosz, February 2015- ongoing; cuid5940; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://sonicempireinc.com/ and http://www.mjdorian.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded Soundcloud audio and Youtube and Vimeo video files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of his works for film, games, and POP creations, news related to his music, page with downloads, and contact information. Jeziorski uses traditional orchestration techniques and modern technology to create compositions for films and games. Capture of the site began in April 2015. This description is based on the July 2017 capture of the site.
  http://www.mjdorian.com/ hosts music and artwork for 'MJ Dorian', which is the alias for composer Milosz Jeziorski's pop and hip hop side-project. The site was first captured in January 2020. This description is based on the 2020 capture of the site.
- Johnson, Jenny Olivia, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5930; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.jennyoliviajohnson.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, a list of her works, news related to her music, and press articles. Johnson's music includes compressed electronic operas, pop songs, abstract chamber works, multi-media meditations using amplified instruments and video, and installation works involving interactive sound and lighting. Capture of the site began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Johnson, Scott, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5912; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.scottjohnsoncomposer.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a list of his compositions, his discography, audio recordings of his works, reviews and articles relating to Johnson, images of the artist, and 5 works of prose written by him. His music blends rock instruments and technology with scored composition and traditional venues to create an updated classical feel. Capture of the website began in June 2017. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Kahane, Gabriel, August 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://gabrielkahane.tumblr.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  "Music" and "Random" pages were not captured due to technological constraints.
- Karlsson, Mikael, November 2015- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://mikaelk.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the pianist and composer Mikael Karlsson, examples of his music in the form of embedded audio files, a discography of his published albums, and information about his works and projects. The compositions featured on the site are classically-influenced chamber, dance, and opera pieces. Capture of the site began in November 2015. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Kathryn, Julie, May 2017- ongoing; cuid5888; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.iamsnowangel.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Images, embedded Soundcloud audio files, and embedded Youtube video files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains a biography of Julie Kathryn (stage name- I am Snow Angel), examples of her compositions and performances in the form of embedded audio and video files, images of the artist and her performances, a calendar of her events, and news about the artist. Kathryn combines electronic elements with traditional instruments and country roots. Site capture began in May 2017. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
  Julie Kathryn Franco (I am Snow Angel) Papers (MSS 480)
  I Am Snow Angel
- Keating, Zoë, April 2014-ongoing; 3 websites in 3 archived websites.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of zoekeating.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Zoë Keating is a composer and cellist. Her website consists of videos of her performances, her composing credits, music used in media, dance and theater credits, a calendar of upcoming events, news, links to press, her tumblr blog which detailed her husband's cancer diagnosis, and a bancamp page with her music. This description is based on the March 2020 crawl.
- Kellogg, Daniel, March 2020-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of https://danielkellogg.blog/ and http://www.danielkellogg.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Daniel Kellogg is a composer based out of the University of Colorado at Boulder. His website contains news and event listings, information on his musical projects, audio and scores, information on how to purchase his music, his composition blog, and his photography. This description is based on the April 2020 crawl.
- Kim, K. Marie, May 2017- ongoing; cuid5889; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://kmariekim.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Parts of the live site involving Soundcloud, Bandcamp, and Youtube were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains examples of her compositions in the form of embedded audio and video files and a biography of the artist. Kim's music incorporates several instruments and electronic elements. She is also a sound engineer and performer on the cello and piano. Capture of the site began in May 2017. This description is based on the July 2017 capture of the site.
  K. Marie Kim Papers (MSS 504)
- Kimura, Mari, July 2017- ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.marikimura.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded video files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of violinist and composer Mari Kimura, examples of her music in the form of embedded audio and video files, a discography of her published albums, reviews of Kimura and her works, and information about her works and projects. The compositions featured on the site are primarily for violin, although she also composes computer music. Capture of the site began in November 2015. This description is based on the July 2017 capture of the site.
  MUGIC, created by Mari Kimura, is a prototype motion sensor that enables one to use movements to control virtually anything in software, specifically used by musicians, dancers, artists, and actors on stages. MUGIC was originally built with the intention of capturing nuanced physical data to control parameters in music software. The website contains tutorials, software downloads, video examples, and testimonials.
- King, John, August 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.johnkingmusic.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded video and Soundcloud audio files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of violist, guitarist, and composer John King, examples of his music in the form of embedded audio files, a discography of his published albums, reviews of King and his works, and a blog. King has composed music for opera, theater, and concert performance. His works are primarily instrumental. Capture of the site began in August 2017. This description is based on the August 2017 capture of the site.
- Kirchoff, Keith, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  new site crawls are accrued semiannually.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://keithkirchoff.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, a calendar of his events, a discography of his published albums, and examples of his works in the form of embedded video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a pianist, conductor, and composer of music that emphasizes experimentation and the merging of technology and classical performance. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the December 2017 capture of the site.
- Kirst, Patrick, February 2014-ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Professional website for film composer Patrick Kirst, which features the composer's film credits, embeded audio samples of a selection of Kirst's work, a biography, and a blog for news and personal updates. The site was first captured in February 2014. The site was updated significantly in 2017, but crawls before that point are not viewable in Wayback due to a playback error which may be resolved at a later date.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of patrickkirst.com and wix.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Kline, Phil, July 2017- ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://philkline.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website documents his work as a composer and performer of chamber music, electronic music, and music inspired and influenced by New York's downtown scene. The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions, examples of his music in the form of embedded audio and video recordings, reviews of his works, a blog about a performance project in which he is involved, and examples of his prose work, which mostly consist of reviews of other musicians and information about his own performances. Capture of the site began in July 2017. This description is based on the July 2017 capture of the site.
  Unsilent Night is an original composition by Phil Kline, written specifically to be heard outdoors in the month of December. It takes the form of a street promenade in which the audience becomes the performer. Each participant gets one of four tracks of music in the form of a cassette, CD, or Mp3. Together all four tracks comprise Unsilent Night. The website contains an annual performance schedule.
- Klucevsek, Guy, May 2017- ongoing; cuid5880; 2 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.guyklucevsek.com/ and http://www.ksanti.net/free-reed/essays/misdemeanors.html in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Some external sites were included due to their contextual value to the site that is the focus of this crawl. These sites are http://www.ksanti.net/free-reed/essays/misdemeanors.html.
  Flash based embedded video and audio files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, his resume, examples of his work in the form of embedded audio and video files, information about his accordions, performances, compositions, and projects, images of Klucevsek, and quotes from the press about the artist. Klucevsek is an accomplished accordionist and a founding member of Accordion Tribe, an ensemble of international composers and accordion players. Capture of the site began in May 2017. This description is based on the May 26, 2017 capture of the site.
  Accordion Tribe
- Kouyoumdjian, Mary, August 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.marykouyoumdjian.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded Vimeo video files and Soundcloud audio files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about her current and past projects, a calendar of her events, and reviews of Kouyoumdjian and her compositions. The works featured on the site include concert pieces, film scores, and multimedia collaborations. Capture of the site began in August 2017. This description is based on the August 2017 capture of the site.
- La Barbara, Joan, July 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.joanlabarbara.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Parts of the live site involving Flash, Javascript, and Soundcloud were not captured due to technological constraints.
  New site crawls accrue annually.